<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alan Hollis</title>
    <link>http://alanhollis.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alan Hollis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://alanhollis.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/thanks/</guid>
      <description> Thanks!  Thank you for getting in contact. I&#39;ll reply as soon as I can.     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testimonials</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/testimonials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/testimonials/</guid>
      <description>p { margin-top: 10px; }  Testimonials  Nice things people have said about me:
Jemma Pink: Director of Corporate Systems, Six Degrees Technology Group Ltd  I directly managed Alan for two years as my Head of Development at Six Degrees Group. We worked closely together on business critical transformation projects where Alan always delivered. Rated by his team as an exceptional manager, he was able to consistently inspire and lead them to deliver technical solutions to specification, within time and to budget constraints necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/about-me/</guid>
      <description>About Me   Leading development teams I&#39;ve learned not just to manage, but to listen, to motivate and to inspire. Through consulting, I&#39;ve learned the art of the sale, the value of long lasting connections and the power of recommendation. As a support engineer I&#39;ve learned to not plaster over problems, but to get to the heart of them.  Programming has, through practice, hard work and dedication, given me the skills and experience to solve problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Building</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/app-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/app-building/</guid>
      <description> App Building     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture      Case Studies  Agricamera   Agricamera is a start-up competing in the CCTV industry. The unique value proposition is that compared to other CCTV providers their solution requires no third party intervention and &#34;just works&#34;.  In order to achieve this goal the architecture needed to tackle the following challenges:  Communicate with cameras behind home routers without the need for customers needing to log on to the router  Allow support staff to diagnose networking problems Platform must be available at all times Customer must have best possible view of camera depending on where they current are, local network / remote viewing  Cameras must be accessible via the widest range of devices Quickly scalable as customer base grows   The bulk of the application is cloud basz , with individual camera controllers running on Agricamera&#39;s customer networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/dev-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/dev-ops/</guid>
      <description>DevOps   Case Studies | Tools | Tutorials     Case Studies  Agricamera.co.uk   Agricamera&#39;s entire software environment was built with DevOps in mind from the start. Before any new software was written careful thought was taken to make sure the development environments were immediately reproducible by issuing just a couple of commands using Vagrant and Ansible. All of Agricamera&#39;s services are cloud based.  This forethought meant deploying to production was just an extension of the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Strategy</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/it-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/it-strategy/</guid>
      <description> IT Strategy      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/marketing/</guid>
      <description> Marketing     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/software-development/</guid>
      <description>Software Development   Portfolio | Tutorials     Portfolio  A summary of some the projects I&#39;m most proud of during my freelance career
Assist-CKD.org   Assist-CKD is a quality improvement project supported by The Health Foundation which is looking to identify patients with a high risk of Chronic Kidney Disease progression.  The application is designed to take data from external systems in the NHS and then allow lab technicians to review the data in a way which makes spotting if a person is likely to be at risk of Chronic Kidney Disease Easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing go with PHP</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/php/comparing-go-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/php/comparing-go-with-php/</guid>
      <description>Go compared with php. Arrays and slices  This is part of a series of articles comparing the language of Go to PHP
Variable assignment  In PHP variable assigned is very simple : $myString = &#34;My String&#34;;   In Go this is a little different. Go is statically typed meaning those familiar with other statically typed languages would expect to see something like String myString = &#34;My String&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/contact/</guid>
      <description> Contact Me     Send     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first month freelancing</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/first-month-freelancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/first-month-freelancing/</guid>
      <description>First Month Freelancing  What I&#39;ve learnt  There is plenty of work out there, for someone who knows what they&#39;re doing. There are a lot of web development companies looking for full time developer roles. It&#39;s hard to say no to full time employment when you&#39;re starting out. Most companies will try to bid you down on price, don&#39;t accept straight away. Reach a compromise that works for you both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first year freelancing</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/my-first-year-freelancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/my-first-year-freelancing/</guid>
      <description>h2 { margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px; } h3 { font-size: 20px; font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif; margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px; } lead { font-size: 10px; }  First Year Freelancing  I&#39;ve always wanted to work for myself. Last year I starting doing just that.
This is what I&#39;ve learned so far: Charge more Working out what to charge is probably the hardest part of working for yourself. When I first started out I was undercharging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>freelance php developer</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/php-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/freelancing/php-developer/</guid>
      <description>h2 { margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px; } h3 { font-size: 20px; font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif; margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 20px; } dd { margin-left: 10px; } lead { font-size: 10px; }  PHP Developer  I&#39;m a PHP developer and I&#39;m available for hire. Contact me.
Why choose me as your PHP developer?  I&#39;m an advanced PHP developer with many years experience. I love the PHP language, despite the criticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go compared with PHP arrays and slices</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/php/go-compared-with-php-arrays-and-slices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/php/go-compared-with-php-arrays-and-slices/</guid>
      <description>Go compared with php. Arrays and slices  Creating   Create an array in PHP $myStringArray = [&#34;One&#34;,&#34;Two&#34;,&#34;Three&#34;];   In Go creating the above is a little more verbose and like variable assignment above there&#39;s also multiple ways to create a slice. The most similar way to that of PHP is as follows. myStringArray := []string{&#34;One&#34;,&#34;Two&#34;,&#34;Three&#34;}  Appending   Things become a little trickier when you want to append to an array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js: Testing a Node.js API with Mocha, Async, and Should</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/javascript/node-js-testing-a-node-js-api-with-mocha-async-and-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/javascript/node-js-testing-a-node-js-api-with-mocha-async-and-should/</guid>
      <description>Node.js: Testing a Node.js API with Mocha, Async, and Should   Application Overview
 The API is broken down into bundles, each bundle is stored in a separate folder and contains a model and a controller.  The application has the following directory structure. -/bundles/ -/bundles/foo/model.js -/bundles/foo/controller.js -/bundles/bar/model.js -/bundles/bar/controller.js  The controllers extend from a base module called controller.js which implements the create/review/update/delete code. Testing the API
 The rest of this article will concentrate on the DELETE api call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving bugs with phpunit and git bisect</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/php/solving-bugs-phpunit-git-bisect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 21:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/php/solving-bugs-phpunit-git-bisect/</guid>
      <description>Solving Bugs With Php Unit and Git Bisect  Sometimes as developers we don’t always catch everything in our test, bugs being the tricky things they are will always slip through the net. When they do we need to fix them, but where do we begin?
The answer, PHPUnit + git bisect, using git bisect and PHPUnit we can quickly narrow down what commit caused the bug, which should allow us to find what caused and therefore solve the bug really quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
