<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software-developments on Alan Hollis</title>
    <link>http://alanhollis.com/software-development/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software-developments on Alan Hollis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://alanhollis.com/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development</title>
      <link>http://alanhollis.com/software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:44:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alanhollis.com/software-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;col&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif;&#34;&gt;

            &lt;div class=&#34;card-block&#34;&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h2
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        Software Development&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;


                &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;#portfolio&#34;&gt;Portfolio &lt;/a&gt;| &lt;a href=&#34;#tutorials&#34;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;col&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif;&#34;&gt;

            &lt;div class=&#34;card-block&#34;&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h2
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;a name=&#34;portfolio&#34;&gt;Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;A summary of some the projects I&#39;m most proud of during my freelance career&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h3
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        Assist-CKD.org&lt;/h3&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Assist-CKD is a quality improvement project supported by The Health Foundation which is looking to
                    identify patients with a high risk of Chronic Kidney Disease progression.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The application is designed to take data from external systems in the NHS and then allow lab
                    technicians
                    to review the data in a way which makes spotting if a person is likely to be at risk of Chronic
                    Kidney Disease
                    Easier.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The existing application had performance and maintenance problems as it was tightly coupled to SQL
                    Server
                    which meant each trust using the software had to purchase an expensive software license in order to
                    take part
                    in the trial. The application was re-written to allow a choice of relational database servers, from
                    MySQL To
                    SQLite.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The incorporation of SQLLite into the software also allowed individual trusts to be up and running
                    as
                    minimal involvement from IT departments were required. The software could be installed and a trust
                    up and
                    running in less than five minutes.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Written using electron.js the application is able to run on multiple environments ( windows, mac )
                    using only one codebase. The wealth of libraries written for node.js also meant the existing
                    application could be re-written quickly, to a greater standard than the original quickly and
                    inexpensively.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Features Include:
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Fast import of CSV files containing millions of records&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Support for multiple databases utilising the sequelize.js library&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Database migrations and squirrel for easy updates to the application&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Automated testing via Karma.js, Phantom.js and Karma-Electron&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h3
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        AgriCamera.co.uk&lt;/h3&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    AgriCamera.co.uk supplies CCTV to the agricultural industry. Due to the remote locations of the
                    installation locations the software had to be designed to work with low bandwidth locations.
                    H.264 was not a viable solution for AgriCamera due to the high latency involved which would render
                    the cameras which ability to move based on user feedback in real-time useless.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    AgriCamera runs a hardware on the customers wifi which then transmits a compressed mjpeg stream to a
                    centralised application
                    built using Node.Js. Transportation of the images is achieved through the use of socket.io. The
                    centralised engine allows
                    a single mjpeg stream to be shared to multiple viewers without increasing the bandwidth usage at the
                    clients site.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    AgriCamera has a mobile application written using Ionic/PhoneGap allowed quick iteration of design
                    and
                    ideas across the most number of devices. The mobile application quickly became one of the most
                    popular
                    ways for clients to access their mobile applications. Particular attention had to be paid to the
                    performance of the application in order to make sure that
                    the quality of the stream remained high. The application also provided a &#34;low bandwidth mode&#34; for
                    those
                    customers who&#39;s mobile signal was often poor.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Features Include:
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Ability to choose multiple streams based on the speed of the customers connection&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Full permissions based viewing of cameras&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Motion Detection based recordings&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Ability to &#34;mask&#34; sections of an image for greater motion accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Automated scalability of service&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Real-time logging and system diagnosis&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Secure remote upates&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    This technology allows AgriCamera to deliver a unique value proposition to their clients.
                &lt;/p&gt;


                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h3
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        The-Hpo.com&lt;/h3&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The HPO provide an online auditing tool to help their clients better understand their businesses.
                    The software driving their auditing tool had become hard to maintain and wasn&#39;t able to cope with
                    the
                    amount of data that The HPO were now handling. The customer front end also lacked visual appeal and
                    needed to become more flexible as customers began looking for more ways to understand their data.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The application required the design and implementation of a data warehouse. Using the techniques
                    from
                    the book &lt;a
                        href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Agile-Data-Warehouse-Design-Collaborative/dp/0956817203&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                    the HPO to build a warehouse which would fit their needs, and incorporate their existing
                    algorithms whilst performing much more effectively than the previous version of the code.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    A reporting front end was creating using Yii which allowed customers to view their reports. The
                    backend
                    involves some non-trivial SQL queries, and careful consideration of what and how to index the data
                    in the
                    MySQL database was needed.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Integration with ordering data was achieved by writing a custom extract transform load application
                    utilising the Apache Camel
                    Library.
                    This allowed The HPO to quickly, easily and robustly build a integration engine between the
                    normalised OLTP database and
                    the OLAP database used for the warehouse.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Features Include:
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Full frontend application allowing customisation of templates and reporting&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Extract Transform Load application&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Design and architecture of a data warehouse&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Full front end reporting system, utilising HighCharts and the Yii Php Framework&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;col&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif;&#34;&gt;

            &lt;div class=&#34;card-block&#34;&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h2
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;a name=&#34;tutorials&#34;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;


                &lt;p&gt;Some of the tutorials guides I&#39;ve written over the years&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;div class=&#34;card-title&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;h3
                            style=&#34;font-weight:bold;font-family: &#39;Nixie One&#39;; margin-bottom: 20px&#34;&gt;
                        PHP&lt;/h3&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alanhollis.com/solving-bugs-phpunit-git-bisect/&#34;&gt;Solving bugs with PHPUnit and git bisect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alanhollis.com/comparing-go-with-php/&#34;&gt;Go compared with PHP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alanhollis.com/go-compared-with-php-arrays-and-slices/&#34;&gt;Go compared with PHP. Arrays and Slices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>